Guide to the Richard Kluger Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional Material, Accession 1997-M-023
  - Company files [contents vary from folder to folder, but may include correspondence, printed materials, working papers, biographical information, and Kluger interview materials]
    - Liggett and Myers
      - Market Planning Corporation, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Gerzog, Lawrence, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Kensler, Charles J., 1963, 1967, 1978, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Mold, James D., 1959-1960, 1988-1992 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Lorillard (P.) Company
      - General, 1937-1960, 1967-1968, 1978, 1987-1992 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Cramer, Morgan, 1961-1966, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Gruber, Lewis, 1956-1970 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Wald, Robert L., 1988 June 9 (Box 2, Folder 16A)
    - Philip Morris Company
      - History [mostly summary notes by Kluger of materials documenting the history of the company, includes some interviews] (Box 3, Folder 20 - 21)
      - Printed [includes other materials], 1935-1989 (Box 3, Folder 22-24)
      - Supplementary, 1940-1983, 1985-1989 (Box 3, Folder 25-26)
      - "The Road to Marlboro Country" [Scott Ellsworth draft], 1987 (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - Promotional and advertising [includes some correspondence], 1987-1990 (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - Promotional and advertising [includes some correspondence], 1988-1992 (Box 4, Folder 29)
      - Additional [consist of news/magazine clippings], 1942-1992 (Box 4, Folder 30)
      - Additional [consist of news/magazine clippings], 1989 October – 1991 May (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - Corporate contributions [includes Philip Morris Quarterly ], 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 32)
      - Corporate image advertising campaign/Bill of Rights tour, 1986-1992 (Box 4, Folder 33)
      - Financial [annual reports]
        - 1948, 1950, 1960, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 34)
        - 1968, 1970, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 35)
        - 1979, 1980, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 36)
        - 1985, 1987, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 37)
        - 1989, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 38)
        - 1991, 1992, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 39)
      - Interviews/biographical
        - Correspondence [includes interview questions, notes], 1988-1992, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
        - Berkowitz, Max L., 1946-1992 (Box 5, Folder 41)
        - Bible, Geoffry C., 1994 (Box 5, Folder 42)
        - Bleakley, Peter, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 43)
        - Bloom, Stephen J., 1991, undated (Box 5, Folder 44)
        - Bowling, James C., 1989 (Box 5, Folder 45)
        - Bring, Murray, 1989-1994 (Box 5, Folder 46)
        - Buccellato, Vincent, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 47)
        - Burnett, Leo, 1935-1971, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 48)
        - Buzzi, Aleardo G., 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 49)
        - Campbell, William L., 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 50)
        - Carlson, Stig G., 1991 (Box 6, Folder 51)
        - Case, Barry, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 52)
        - Charles, Jim, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 53)
        - Crenshaw, Gordon [Universal leaf] and Jordan, Daniel P., 1991 (Box 6, Folder 54)
        - Cullman, Edgar M., 1961, 1976, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 55)
        - Cullman, Hugh, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 56)
        - Cullman, Joseph F., III, 1957-1980
          See also: box 7, folder 102
          - 1957-1980 (Box 6, Folder 57)
          - 1984-1992 (Box 6, Folder 58)
        - Cullman, W. (William) Arthur, 1951, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 59)
        - Dangoor, David E.R., 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 60)
        - Dunn, William L., 1987 (Box 6, Folder 61)
        - Gallaher Limited, 1968, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 62)
        - Gembler, Andreas, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 63)
        - Gillis, John J., 1989 (Box 6, Folder 64)
        - Goldsmith, Clifford H., 1989, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 65)
        - Greenberg, David I., 1991 (Box 6, Folder 66)
        - Hatcher, Wirt H., Jr., 1972, 1987, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 67)
        - Holtzman, Alexander, 1970, 1989, 1990, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 68)
        - Houminer, Ehud, 1989-1991 (Box 6, Folder 69)
        - Jeblee, J. Paul, 1935, 1969, 1978, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 70)
        - Krash, Abe, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 71)
        - Landor, Walter, 1985, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 72)
        - Landry, John T., 1968-1991 (Box 6, Folder 73)
        - Lincoln, Jetson E., 1984, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 74)
        - Littleton, C. Thomas and Diane Crouch, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 75)
        - Lloyd, Joseph, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 76)
        - Lyon, Alfred E., 1938-1967, 1989, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 77)
        - Maxwell, Hamish, 1988-1994 (Box 7, Folder 78)
        - McDowell, W. Wallace, Jr., 1991 (Box 7, Folder 79)
        - McQuigg, Edwin J., 1991, undated (Box 7, Folder 80)
        - Merlo, Ellen, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 81)
        - Miles, Michael A., 1989-1994 (Box 7, Folder 82)
        - Millhiser, Ross R., 1978-1993 (Box 7, Folder 83)
        - Morgan, James J., 1984-1989 (Box 7, Folder 84)
        - Murphy, John A., 1989-1991 (Box 7, Folder 85)
        - Murray, William, 1989-1991 (Box 7, Folder 86)
        - Osdene, Thomas S., 1992 (Box 7, Folder 87)
        - Parrish, Steven C., 1991 (Box 7, Folder 88)
        - Pollack, Shepard P., 1991 (Box 7, Folder 89)
        - Pollak, Lee, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 90)
        - Resnik, Frank E., 1989 (Box 7, Folder 91)
        - Richman, John M., 1991 (Box 7, Folder 92)
        - Schoenkopf, Richard, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 93)
        - Smith, Guy L., IV, 1986-1991 (Box 7, Folder 94)
        - Wilson, Don W. [National Archives for the Bill of Rights bicentennial], 1991 (Box 7, Folder 95)
        - Storr, Hans G., 1989-1991 (Box 7, Folder 96)
        - Thoma, Walter, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 97)
        - Thomson, Ronald Hew, undated (Box 7, Folder 98)
        - Vail, Richard G., 1990 (Box 7, Folder 99)
        - Wakeham, Helmut R.R., 1960-1993 (Box 7, Folder 100)
        - Weissman, George, 1958-1989 (Box 7, Folder 101)
        - Wertenbaker, Lael Tucker [photocopy of Mister Junior, a biographical work on Joseph F. Cullman, Jr.], 1960 (Box 7, Folder 102)
          See also: box 6, folders 57-58
      - "The Philip Morris Century: A Story of Men and Products with a Special Blend of Related Anecdotes" ["unpublished, authorized history"]
        - Pp. 1-210, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 103)
        - Pp. 211-459, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 104)
        - Pp. 460-496, unnumbered pages, additional pages 3-39 (index), a continuation through 1961 (Box 8, Folder 105)
        - Index pp. 30-138, first and second continuation 1-73, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 106)
        - Pp. 74-198, fourth continuation pp. 1-72 (Box 8, Folder 107)
        - Fourth continuation pp. 73-285, index pp. 1-26 (Box 8, Folder 108)
      - Philip Morris Magazine
        - 1986 (Box 8, Folder 109)
        - 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 110)
        - 1989 (Box 9, Folder 111)
        - 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 112)
      - The Philip Morris Globe, 1990 Jun, Dec, 1991 May (Box 9, Folder 113)
      - Proxy statements, 1978-1989 (Box 9, Folder 114)
      - Marlboro Oral History Project [interview with company employees focusing on the "Marlboro Country" advertising campaign, and related printed material], 1958, 1977-1978, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 115)
      - Shareholders annual meeting [includes correspondence], 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 116)
    - R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Company
      - Correspondence [includes interview questions and notes], 1986-1991 (Box 9, Folder 117)
      - History [mostly summary notes by Kluger of materials documenting the history of the company] (Box 9, Folder 118)
      - Printed [includes other materials]
        - 1931-1971 (Box 9, Folder 119)
        - 1976-1986 (Box 9, Folder 120)
        - 1987-1988 (Box 10, Folder 121)
        - 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 122)
        - 1990-1992 (Box 10, Folder 123)
      - Annual reports, 1987, 1990, 1991, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 124)
      - Interviews/biographical
        - Davis, John W., III, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 125)
        - Fishel, David B. [includes photographs], 1989-1991 (Box 10, Folder 126)
        - Ford, Yancey W., Jr., 1991 (Box 10, Folder 127)
        - Griscom, Thomas C., 1991 (Box 10, Folder 128)
        - Horrigan, Edward J., 1991 (Box 10, Folder 129)
        - Johnston, James W., 1991, undated (Box 10, Folder 130)
        - Katz, Stanley H., 1976, 1991, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 131)
        - Smith, Zachary, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 132)
        - Sticht, J. Paul, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 133)
        - Wade, Charles B, Jr., undated (Box 10, Folder 134)
      - Obituaries of board members, 1949, 1953, 1958, 1969, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 135)
    - Tobacco industry files
      - Advertising/promotion
        - General [mostly summary notes by Kluger of materials documenting the history of the industry] (Box 11, Folder 136)
        - Printed [includes other materials]
          - 1928-1969 (Box 11, Folder 137)
          - 1969-1989 (Box 11, Folder 138)
          - 1954-1991 (Box 11, Folder 139)
      - Growers/history [summary notes by Kluger, printed material], 1949-1992 (Box 11, Folder 140)
      - International Issues
        - General [mostly summary notes by Kluger of printed materials] (Box 11, Folder 141)
        - Printed, 1986-1989 (Box 11, Folder 142)
        - Printed
          - 1947-1988 (Box 12, Folder 143)
          - 1987-1989 (Box 12, Folder 144)
          - 1989-1992 (Box 12, Folder 145)
      - Lobbying/Industry Promotion
        - General [mostly summary notes by Kluger] (Box 12, Folder 146)
        - Printed, 1964-1991 (Box 12, Folder 147)
      - Marketing
        - General [mostly summary notes by Kluger] (Box 12, Folder 148)
        - Reports/printed materials [includes other materials], 1932-1965 (Box 12, Folder 149)
        - Reports/printed materials [includes other materials], 1966-1988 (Box 12, Folder 150)
        - Reports/printed materials [includes other materials], 1987-1989 (Box 13, Folder 151)
        - Appendix, 1931-1994 (Box 13, Folder 152-154)
      - Sales, 1925-1991, undated (Box 13, Folder 155)
      - Tobacco Institute (Washington, D.C.)
        - General [summary notes by Kluger] (Box 13, Folder 156)
        - Printed [includes other materials], 1978, undated (Box 13, Folder 157)
        - Printed [includes other materials]
          - 1959-1971 (Box 13, Folder 158)
          - 1977-1979, no date (Box 14, Folder 159)
          - 1979-1982, no date (Box 14, Folder 160)
          - 1957-1967, 1982-1989 (Box 14, Folder 161)
          - 1984-1986 (Box 14, Folder 162)
          - 1985-1988 (Box 14, Folder 163)
          - 1985-1987 (Box 14, Folder 164)
          - 1985-1992 (Box 14, Folder 165)
        - Interviews/biographical
          - Allen, George V., 1957-1970, undated (Box 15, Folder 166)
          - Clements, Earle, 1956-1985 (Box 15, Folder 167)
          - DeHart, Edward, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 168)
          - Dwyer, William F. [and Connie Drath], 1979, 1989, undated (Box 15, Folder 169)
          - Kloepfer, William Jr. [correspondence], 1988 (Box 15, Folder 170)
          - Kornegay, Horace R., 1964-1984 (Box 15, Folder 171)
          - Liebengood, Howard, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 172)
          - Merryman, Walker, 1990-1991 (Box 15, Folder 173)
          - Whitley, Charles, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 174)
          - Executives [includes Council for Tobacco Research], 1953-1988 (Box 15, Folder 175)
        - Cigarette Smoking and Cancer [scientific perspective], 1982 (Box 15, Folder 176)
      - Council for Tobacco Research (CTR) [prior to 1963 known as Tobacco Industry Research Committee (TIRC)]
        - Reports
          - 1956-1990 (Box 15, Folder 177)
          - 1976?, 1983, 1991-1992 (Box 15, Folder 178)
        - "Chronic Exposure of Mice to Cigarette Smoke" [includes final report with related correspondence and printed material], 1963, 1984-1985, 1991-1992 (Box 15, Folder 179)
      - Health Advocacy Center, CA
        - Sixty Years of Deception: An Analysis and Compilation of Cigarette Ads in Time Magazine, 1925-1985 [ privately published], 1986
          - Vol. I, 1925-1939 (Box 15, Folder 180)
          - Vol. II, 1940-1953 (Box 16, Folder 181)
          - Vol. III, 1954-1963 (Box 16, Folder 182)
          - Vol. IV, 1964-1973 (Box 16, Folder 183)
          - Vol. V, 1974-1985 (Box 16, Folder 184)
    - Personal interviews [non-industry, includes surgeons, pathologists, statisticians, lawyers, etc.]
      - Adams, Lane W., 1988 (Box 17, Folder 185)
      - Auerbach, Oscar, 1956-1970, 1986, undated (Box 17, Folder 186)
      - Auerbach, Oscar, 1970-1988 (Box 17, Folder 187)
      - Auerbach, Oscar, 1966-1991 (Box 17, Folder 188)
      - Baker, Carl G., 1977, 1986, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 189)
      - Banzhaf, John F., III, 1973-1990 (Box 17, Folder 190)
      - Barfield, Rebecca (Becky), 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 191)
      - Barr, Glenn/Braude, Marvin, 1987-1989 (Box 17, Folder 192)
      - Benowitz, Neal L., 1986-1991 (Box 17, Folder 193)
      - Berkson, Joseph, 1953-1989 (Box 17, Folder 194)
      - Bing, Richard J., 1975, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 195)
      - Blum, Alan, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 196)
      - Braren, Warren, 1967, 1970-1974, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 197)
      - Brecher, Edward, 1979, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 198)
      - Breslow, Lester, 1977-1989 (Box 17, Folder 199)
      - Brown, Byron W., Jr., 1989, undated (Box 17, Folder 200)
      - Burney, Leroy E., 1957-1962, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 201)
      - Burns, David M., 1989 (Box 17, Folder 202)
      - Burry, Roy D., 1988-1992 (Box 17, Folder 203)
      - Cahan, William G., 1968, 1983, 1985, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 204)
      - Califano, Joesph A., Jr., 1978-1988 (Box 18, Folder 205)
      - Cameron, Charles S., 1954-1956, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 206)
      - Cohen, Stanley, 1963-1969, 1988-1989 (Box 18, Folder 207)
      - Connolly, Gregory N., 1875, 1986, 1988, undated (Box 18, Folder 208)
      - Cullen, Joseph W., 1987-1988 (Box 18, Folder 209)
      - Davis, Alan C., 1989 (Box 18, Folder 210)
      - Davis, Ronald M., 1986-1991 (Box 18, Folder 211)
      - Daynard, Richard A., 1987-1992 (Box 18, Folder 212)
      - Dingell, John, 1972, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 213)
      - Dixon, Paul Randall, 1961-1977 (Box 18, Folder 214)
      - Doll, Richard, 1952-1982 (Box 18, Folder 215)
      - Duster, Troy, 1987, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 216)
      - Edell, Marc Z./Walters, Cynthia, 1987-1990 (Box 18, Folder 217)
      - Elman, Philip, undated (Box 18, Folder 218)
      - Farber, Emmanuel, 1988-1989 (Box 18, Folder 219)
      - Fielding, Johnathan E., 1989 (Box 18, Folder 220)
      - Foote, Emerson, 1964-1965, 1977, 1981, 1987, undated (Box 18, Folder 221)
      - Forbes, E. Ripley, undated (Box 18, Folder 222)
      - Ford, Wendell, 1983, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 223)
      - Fountain, L.H., 1962 (Box 18, Folder 224)
      - Garfinkel, Lawrence, 1984, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 225)
      - Geller, Henry, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 226)
      - Glantz, Stanton A., 1978-1992 (Box 18, Folder 227 - 228)
      - Glasser, Irving, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 229)
      - Goldman, Emanuel, 1985, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 230)
      - Gori, Gio B., 1959, 1972-1989 (Box 19, Folder 231)
      - Graham, Evarts, A., 1952, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 232)
      - Gritz, Ellen, 1986-1989 (Box 19, Folder 233)
      - Hamill, Peter V., 1963-1988 (Box 19, Folder 234)
      - Hammond, Edward Cuyler, 1953-1988 (Box 19, Folder 235)
      - Harken, Dwight E., 1968-1989 (Box 19, Folder 236)
      - Harlan, William, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 237)
      - Harris, Jeffrey E., 1987-1989 (Box 19, Folder 238)
      - Hitchcock, Jan L., 1988 (Box 19, Folder 239)
      - Hoffman, Dietrich, 1988-1991, undated (Box 19, Folder 240)
      - Holleb, Arthur I., 1988 (Box 19, Folder 241)
      - Homburger, Freddy, 1974-1988, undated (Box 19, Folder 242)
      - Horn, Daniel, 1949, 1969-1972, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 243)
      - Hutchings, Robert, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 244)
      - Hutter, Robert V.P., 1989 (Box 20, Folder 245)
      - Jarvik, Murray E., 1970-1992 (Box 20, Folder 246)
      - Jonas, Allan K., 1989 (Box 20, Folder 247)
      - Karnovsky, Manfred L., 1986 (Box 20, Folder 248)
      - Kessler, David A., 1995 (Box 20, Folder 249)
      - Knapp, Peter H., 1955, 1963, 1970, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 250)
      - Koop, C. Everett, 1979-1989 (Box 20, Folder 251)
      - Kotin, Paul, 1954-1980 (Box 20, Folder 252)
      - Kozlowski, Lynn T., 1975-1988 (Box 20, Folder 253)
      - Le Maistre, Charles A., 1971-1989 (Box 20, Folder 254)
      - Levin, Morton L., 1950-1989 (Box 20, Folder 255)
      - Little, Clarence C., 1929-1979 (Box 20, Folder 256)
      - Loveday, Paul, 1978-1994 (Box 20, Folder 257)
      - Lowry, P. Dennis, 1991 (Box 20, Folder 258)
      - Magnuson, Warren G., 1956-1980 (Box 20, Folder 259)
      - Maxwell, John C., Jr., 1991, 1993 (Box 21, Folder 260)
      - McCarthy, William J., 1987-1989 (Box 21, Folder 261)
      - McGuire, Andrew, 1980-1989 (Box 21, Folder 262)
      - Merlis, Edward A., 1988 (Box 21, Folder 263)
      - Moffitt, Toby, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 264)
      - Morgan, Charles, Jr., 1988 (Box 21, Folder 265)
      - Morrison, Bayard H., III, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 266)
      - Moss, Frank E., 1964-1972 (Box 21, Folder 267)
      - Moss, John E., Jr., 1956-1972 (Box 21, Folder 268)
      - Myers, Matthew L., 1987 (Box 21, Folder 269)
      - Nader, Ralph, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 270)
      - Neuberger, Maurine B., 1957-1961 (Box 21, Folder 271)
      - Newell, Guy R., 1988-1989 (Box 21, Folder 272)
      - Ochsner, Alton, 1940-1988 (Box 21, Folder 273)
      - Overholt, Richard H., 1964-1988 (Box 21, Folder 274)
      - Owen, Thomas B., 1988 (Box 21, Folder 275)
      - Pearl, Raymond K., 1927-1940 (Box 21, Folder 276)
      - Pertschuk, Michael, 1971-1981 (Box 21, Folder 277)
      - Pertschuk, Michael, 1982-1988 (Box 21, Folder 278)
      - Pertschuk, Michael, 1988-1992 (Box 21, Folder 279)
      - Pertschuk, Michael, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 280)
      - Pinney, John M., 1988 (Box 22, Folder 281)
      - Pitofsky, Robert, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 282)
      - Rauscher, Frank J., Jr., 1989 (Box 22, Folder 283)
      - Read, Clifton, 1988-1989 (Box 22, Folder 284)
      - Relman, Arnold S., 1988 (Box 22, Folder 285)
      - Repace, James L., 1980-1990 (Box 22, Folder 286 - 287)
      - Richmond, Julius B., 1980, 1986, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 288)
      - Rimer, Irving, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 289)
      - Roemer, Ruth, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 290)
      - Rose, Charles (Charlie) G., undated (Box 22, Folder 291)
      - Saffiotti, Umberto, 1970, 1977, 1987, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 292)
      - Schelling, Thomas C., 1988 (Box 22, Folder 293)
      - Schneiderman, Marvin A., 1978, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 294)
      - Schuman, Leonard M., 1981-1988 (Box 22, Folder 295)
      - Seidman, Herbert, 1963-1988 (Box 22, Folder 296)
      - Seltzer, Carl C., 1979-1993 (Box 22, Folder 297)
      - Selzer, Richard, 1976, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 298)
      - Shopland, Donald, 1988-1989 (Box 22, Folder 299)
      - Singer, Ira, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 300)
      - Sonnenberg, Benjamin, 1979, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 301)
      - Sosnick, Ronald B., 1991 (Box 22, Folder 302)
      - Staggers, Harley O., 1971 (Box 22, Folder 303)
      - Steinfeld, Jesse L., 1971-1991 (Box 22, Folder 304)
      - Stellman, Steven D., 1981-1989 (Box 22, Folder 305)
      - Stokes, Joseph, III, 1988, undated (Box 22, Folder 306)
      - Strauss, Peter, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 307)
      - Sweda, Edward L., Jr., 1988 (Box 23, Folder 308)
      - Tarr-Whelan, Keith, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 309)
      - Terry, Luther L., 1961, 1962, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 310)
      - Tollison, Robert D., 1988 (Box 23, Folder 311)
      - Ubell, Earl, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 312)
      - Upton, Arthur C., 1988 (Box 23, Folder 313)
      - Walden, John T., 1988-1989 (Box 23, Folder 314)
      - Waxman, Henry A., 1976-1990 (Box 23, Folder 315)
      - Weisberg, Raymond, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 316)
      - Weisburger, Elizabeth K., 1983, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 317)
      - Wilkenfeld, Judith, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 318)
      - Wynder, Ernest L., 1954-1991 (Box 23, Folder 319 - 320)
      - Yesner, Raymond, 1973, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 321)
      - Zarski, Michael, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 322)
    - Health/scientific aspects
      - "An Analysis of 'R.J. Reynolds' Position Paper on the Health Effects of Smoking'" [John Slade], 1986-1987 (Box 23, Folder 323)
      - Behavior
        - Kluger notes (Box 23, Folder 324)
        - Interviews with friends (Box 23, Folder 325)
      - Cessation [summary notes by Kluger] (Box 23, Folder 326)
      - Economic costs/price supports [summary notes by Kluger] (Box 23, Folder 327)
      - Environmental Tobacco Smoke (ETS) [summary notes by Kluger] (Box 23, Folder 328)
      - "Expert's report on State of the Art" [Jeffrey E. Harris; includes related materials], 1985-1986 (Box 23, Folder 329)
      - "Framingham Study Data and 'Established Wisdom' about Cigarette Smoking and Coronary Heart Disease" [Carl C. Seltzer; includes related material], 1976, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 330)
      - Pharmacology [summary notes by Kluger] (Box 23, Folder 331)
      - A Safe Cigarette [Banbury report], 1980 (Box 24, Folder 332)
      - Surgeon General's Advisory Committee [material from the National Archives], 1962-1964 (Box 24, Folder 333)
      - United States Environmental Protection Agency, 1991 (Box 24, Folder 334)
      - Women and smoking [summary notes by Kluger] (Box 24, Folder 335)
      - Printed material, miscellaneous
        - 1927-1957 (Box 24, Folder 336-346)
        - 1958-1973 (Box 25, Folder 347-361)
        - 1974-1986 (Box 26, Folder 362-374)
        - 1987-1989 (Box 27, Folder 375-377)
    - Antismoking movement
      - General [summary notes by Kluger of printed materials by organization] (Box 27, Folder 378)
      - Action on Smoking and Health (ASH) [Banzhaf, John F.], 1966-1990 (Box 27, Folder 379)
      - American Cancer Society (ACS), 1951-1990 (Box 27, Folder 380)
      - American Council on Science and Health (ACSH), 1979-1992 (Box 27, Folder 381)
      - American Heart Association (AHA) [Ballin, Scott D.], undated (Box 27, Folder 382)
      - American Lung Association (ALA), 1985-1992 (Box 27, Folder 383)
      - American Medical Association (AMA), 1958, 1970, 1986-1990 (Box 28, Folder 384)
      - Americans for Nonsmokers' Rights (ANR), 1981-1991 (Box 28, Folder 385 - 386)
      - California Dept. of Health Services, Tobacoo Education media Campaign commercials, Undated (Box 28, Folder 386A)
      - Coalition on Smoking or Health, 1983-1989 (Box 28, Folder 387)
      - Coalition on Smoking or Health [Myers, Matthew L.], 1985-1987, undated (Box 28, Folder 388)
      - Doctors Ought to Care (DOC) [Blum, Alan], 1979-1988 (Box 28, Folder 389)
      - Doctors Ought to Care, 1989-1992 (Box 28, Folder 390)
      - Group Against Smoking Pollution (GASP) – Massachussetts, 1984-1989, undated (Box 28, Folder 391)
      - Harvard Institute for the Study of Smoking Behavior and Policy, undated (Box 28, Folder 392)
        See also: box 30, folder 404
      - National Cancer Institute (NCI), 1954-1979
        - 1954-1979 (Box 29, Folder 393)
        - 1959, 1980-1986 (Box 29, Folder 394)
        - 1987-1988 (Box 29, Folder 395)
      - National Conference on Smoking or Health [initiated by American Cancer Society], 1981 (Box 29, Folder 396)
      - National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute (NHLBI), 1987-1988 (Box 29, Folder 397)
      - San Diego County Council on Smoking and Health Education [final report of community project], 1974 September (Box 29, Folder 398)
      - Stop Teenage Addiction to Tobacco (STAT), [Tye, Joe B.], 1985-1990, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 399)
      - Stop Teenage Addiction to Tobacco (STAT) Speaker's Guide and Slide Collection [By Joe B. Tye], 1991 (Box 30, Folder 400)
      - U. S. Department of Health and Human Services, Office on Smoking and Health, 1969-1989 (Box 30, Folder 401)
    - Smoking behavior
      - Interview notes, 1987-1990 (Box 30, Folder 402)